## BARIS TEMEL

Mobile Phone:+90(539) 747-7377 ♦ Address:Istanbul, Turkey

 $E-Mail:btemel@sabanciuniv.edu \diamond LinkedIn:https://www.linkedin.com/in/baris-temel/ \diamond Portfolio:https://btemel.github.io/linkedin.com/in/baris-temel/ \diamond Portfolio:https://btemel.github.com/in/baris-temel/ \diamond Portfolio:https://btemel/ openless.github.com/in/baris-temel/ openless.github.com/$ 

#### **SUMMARY**

I hold an Industrial Engineering degree from Sabanci University and an M.Sc. in Data Science from Sabanci University. I have 5 years of experience in data analytics, visualization, business intelligence, and data science fields.

I am a pro at self-management and a quick learner. I am a cheerful and solution-oriented person with decent communication skills, and I have a genuine interest in hot data science topics. Hence, I enjoy what I'm doing.

#### **SKILLS**

Software Languages
Python, SQL, R, Matlab, C++
OpenAI, LangChain, Pinecone, Pytorch, Tensorflow, Spark, Numpy, Scikit, Matplotlib
Tools
Azure Cloud Services, MS Copilot, Power BI & Tableau, Git, Docker, Jira, MS Office
Prompt Engineering, Communication, Resilience, Public Speaking, Time Management

EXPERIENCE

# Data Scientist The Coca-Cola Company

02/2023 - Present Istanbul, Turkey

- Working on building Data Science & Advanced Analytics solutions for cross-functional teams.
- Using Microsoft Azure Platforms to utilize Data Science solutions.
- Building & Improving Gen AI Applications using multiple LLMs. Working on use cases such as harmonizing using vector search, recommendation engine, and integrating Plugins and Assistants to our work stream.
- Harmonizing multiple external data sources such as Macroeconomics, Weather, and COVID Mobility with our company data and creating meaningful Insights & ML Solutions.
- Working on Clustering & Key Driver Analysis solutions for top 40 countries.
- Improving Coca-Cola Data Governance processes on EME OU over 25 countries. Responsible for the improvement & validation tasks of Nielsen who is a leader in delivering marketing information.
- Constructed an in-house Revenue Time Series forecasting solution on BIP (Business Integrated Planner), making a first for the EME. By consolidating various data sources, we successfully completed data modeling and visualization for the MVP of the Benchmark Tool.

## Data Scientist REEF

08/2021 - 05/2022  $Miami. \ US$ 

- Responsible for designing and implementing BI solutions mainly to Kitchen verticals for Strategy and Operational KPIs.
- Architect and build Tableau Dashboards to achieve stakeholder needs.
- Created data structures using REST APIs / SQL / Python.
- Developed Supply Chain Dashboards for Pareto Analysis& Inventory Management System.
- Developed Market Analysis by creating automated scrapers in Python using state of art libraries such as Beautiful Soup, and Selenium.
- Analyzed sentiment analysis on partner delivery service platforms for executives.
- Developed a dashboard for tracking the performance of new employees' training development.
- Developed and improved the back end of over 20 Kitchen Dashboards using Redshift.

Teaching Assistant Sabanci University 09/2020 - 06/2022 Istanbul, Turkey

- Taught as an assistant for the introductory Python programming course IF 100 Computational Approaches to Problem Solving.
- Managed to teach up to intermediate-level concepts on coding to freshman students in one term for about 14 weeks.

## Data Analyst QNB Finansbank

03/2019 - 06/2020*Istanbul*, *Turkey* 

- Management trainee: Trained financial and leadership skills, Python, SQL, and Excel training, and finished a project about credit card fraud detection.
- Koc University MT-MBA Education Program: Learned about macroeconomics, data analytics, and visualizations in real-world problems. The lectures give an insight into the MBA program.
- Analyzed raw data about financial concepts, creating algorithms and models in both Python and R gathering and exporting data using SQL, automating reports, and creating a visual platform in Visual Studio using C# and SQL, experiencing in creating different dashboards and making financial data analysis.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Masters of Science - MS, Data Science, Sabanci University

09/2020 - 12/2022

- Relevant Coursework: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Big Data Processing, Deep NLP, Computer Graphics, Methods of Statistical Inference, Engineering Optimization, Advanced Statistics with R
- GPA: 3.50/4.00

## Bachelor of Industrial Engineering, Sabanci University

09/2014 - 12/2018

- Relevant Coursework: Statistical Modelling, Deterministic & Stochastic Models in Operational Research, Financial Engineering, Decision Analysis, Simulation, Differential Equations, Supply Chain Practice, Quality Planning & Control, Decision Economics, Microeconomics
- GPA: 3.01/4.00

#### **PROJECTS**

Follower Anomalies in Social Media: This is my thesis project. The motivation is to create an open-source algorithm that detects anomalies of followers in any social media. Twitter is my base target social media. I am analyzing social bot movements. You can read the full thesis from this url. (Sabanci University 22')

School Projects: Statistical Inference Tools, Sphere Guided 3D Shape Generation and Manipulation, Face image generation with variational autoencoder, Deep Reinforcement Learning Project in Simulating Natural Selection Environment

Private Projects: Cryptocurrency Price Trend Prediction Learning using LSTM Networks

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

• Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO) by Scrum Alliance